Guide to the Lynne Sagalyn Research Files for "Power at Ground Zero" 1972-2016 MS 3128
New-York Historical Society
- Series XI. Digital Files, 1970s-2016; 18 Gigabytes (2,743 digital files)
  - Subseries XI.A. SAGALYN_PAGZ-PRIMARY-MATERIALS, 1970s-2016; 18 Gigabytes (2,543 digital files)
    - SPI_Larry Silverstein, circa 2000-2012 (Digital file MS3128)
      This folder includes 216 files in PDF, Word, JPEG, and TIFF formats, with a set of video files (BUP, IFO, & VOB), circa 2000-12. About 37 of the files concern the involvement of Larry Silverstein and Silverstein Properties in the World Trade Center site redevelopment planning generally. Those files include letters between Silverstein and the PANYNJ, a risk report on the WTC prepared for Silverstein Properties in 2000, agreements, public statements and testimony, presentations, news articles, and other related documents. The larger balance of files includes specific plans and images for 1 WTC (Freedom Tower), 2 WTC (200 Greenwich Street), 4 WTC (150 Greenwich), and 7 WTC (250 Greenwich). Those files include fact sheets and press kits about the buildings and the architects (Skidmore, Owings & Merrill/SOM, Foster and Partners, and Maki and Associates) and other design collaborators. Images include architectural elevations and other renderings, site plans, samples of other work by the architects, construction of the Freedom Tower, and other views.
    - Third-Party-reports, 2000-2015 (Digital file MS3128)
      This folder includes 58 files, mostly in PDF and Word format, with some text (RTF & TXT), PowerPoint (PPTX), web page (HTML), and Excel formats, 2000-15. The folder includes reports, analyses, articles, conference proceedings, and other pieces prepared by organizations or individuals other than the Port Authority, Lower Manhattan Development Corporation, and others directly involved in the redevelopment. The reports are organized in subject-oriented sub-folders, including: 911-Impacts (10 files), with reports from New York Appraisal Institute, Citizens Housing and Planning Council (CHPC), Multidisciplinary Center for Earthquake Engineering Research (MCEER), and others; Design-Reports (3 files); Economic-Reports_Market-Data (35 files), especially related to real estate market data; and Transportation (5 files) and Other (5 files), with papers from the NYU-Wagner Rudin Center for Transportation Policy & Management and others.
  - Subseries XI.B. Work Product Files, 2003-2016; 48 Megabytes (200 digital files)
    The subseries includes 200 digital files, almost entirely in Microsoft Excel and Word formats, of Lynne Sagalyn's "work product" developed during her and her assistants' research. These include chronologies; notes on press conferences, seminars, presentations, and other events; spreadsheets of calculations; notes on readings of annual reports, agreements, proposals, and other documents; questions, analyses, comparisons and other interpretative work guiding or stemming from the research; media logs; and other material.
    There are about 29 chronologies in the subseries. These include a "master" chronology of about 113 pages that sketches the redevelopment effort from 2001-2013. Other chronologies center on particular aspects of the effort, such as those concerning Liberty Bonds and the Lower Manhattan Construction Command Center. Similarly, about 12 media logs, including a "master" log, track research resources from print and other media sources.
    A full manifest in Excel format of the individual files comprising the subseries is available from the reference librarian on request.
    - 1_0_Chronologies (29 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 2_0_Planning-and-Process (6 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 3_0_Design_ArchCriticism (7 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 4_0_Politics (1 file) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 5_0_Delay_Construction (9 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 6_0_Episode-and-Event-Notes (46 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 7_0_Cultural_Program (3 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 8_0_Memorial_Museum (11 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 9_0_Transportation (8 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 10_0_Rebuilding_Economics_Agreements_Negotiations (31 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 11_0_Insurance (2 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 12_0_Financing (4 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 13_0_Press (5 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 14_0_People_Firms (16 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 15_0_Exhibits_and_Charts (7 files) (Digital file MS3128)
    - 16_Media_Logs (12 files) (Digital file MS3128)
- Series XII. Restricted Files, 1 Linear feet
  One box of documents, primarily interviews, is restricted from access until March 2039 in accordance with the conditions of the donation.
  - Restricted files (Offsite-box 14)